Dirk Hornung, Ph.D.

City: Barcelona

Date of birth: 5th of October, 1991
Place of birth: Fulda, Germany
Mobile: +34 695460404

E-mail: dirkhornung91@gmail.com Website: www.dirkhornung.com



Dear Hays,

I am Dirk Hornung, a recently graduated Ph.D. student at the institute of high energy physics of the autonomous university of Barcelona with 5+ years of experience in leading the technology in different Startups. Within my studies I researched low-energy QCD and the determination of Standard Model parameters. In principle I found intelligent ways to extract parameters of theoretical models out of experimental data.

Apart from my studies I am an entrepreneur. The last year I developed Smart Contracts in the Ethereum blockchain and connected them through REST APIs using Node Express for a legaltech. Before I developed a chatbot using artificial intelligence for a fintech. We connected our clients through Messenger to their bank accounts and analysed their banking information using Python. I am furthermore a Full stack developer with lots of experience developing applications using React as a frontend and AWS services as a backend.

I am very confident that I would be an excellent choice for any upcoming challenge!

Sincerely,

Dr. Dirk Hornung

P.S. I am a native german, but also fluent in english, french and spanish.

Professional Experience

May 2019 - Jan. 2019 **CYSAE**

CTO

Utility Token for Cuatre Casas, Certifying documents with the help of Ethereum, Enterprise Democracy on Chain

Tech: Solidty, Ethereum, Node, Express, React, Redux, GraphQL,

Prisma, NoSQL, Docker, AWS S3

https://www.cysae.com/

Oct. 2017 - Apr. 2018 Alda

CTO & Co-Founder

Fintech Chatbot helping Millenials in Financial Education

Python, NLP, AWS Lambda, Dialogflow, Facebook API, React, Redux,

PostgreSQL, Serverless Feb. 2017 - Sept. 2017

WeGoLoco

 $CTO\ \mathcal{C}\ Co ext{-}Founder$

Matchin Tinder with the Local Commerce

Swift, iOS, AWS S3, NoSQL

Education

2015 - 2019 Ph.D., Theoretical Physics, Autonomous University of Barcelona (Spain)

Thesis: The QCD Strong Coupling from Hadronic Tau Decays

Supervisor: Dr. Matthias Jamin

Created a numerical C++ fitting routine from scretch.

2014 - 2015 M.Sc., Particle Physics, Autonomous University of Barcelona (Spain)

Thesis: 1-Loop Anomalous Dimensions of 4-Quark Operators

Supervisor: Dr. Matthias Jamin

2011 - 2014 B.Sc., Condensed Matter Physics, Goethe University Frankfurt (Germany)

Thesis: Band Structure Studies of Graphene and Modified Graphene Structure

Supervisor: Prof. Dr. Roser Valentí

Skills

Blockchain Ethereum, Solidty, Smart Contracts, ERC20, ERC725, ICOs

Data Science Python, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Tensorflow, SVM, ANN, Mathematica

Frontend Javascript, React (Hooks), React Native, Redux, Spring, CSS, HTML

Backend AWS, Node, Express, MySQL, Postgress, Node, DynamoDB, Serverless, Flask,

Zappa, Django

Prototyping Arduino, C++, Fusion 360, 3d Printing, CNC, Electronics

Marketing Photoshop, Illustrator, Final Cut Pro, SEO, SEM, Wordpress, PHP

Soft Leadership, Public Speaking, Motivating, Mentoring, Confidence, Energy

Languages

German: native
English: proficient
Spanish: proficient
French: intermediate

Hungarian: basics